# **CAMERON ADAMS** | camthehuman.com

camgadams@gmail.com | +27 83 554 2241 | 57 Sardinia Drive, Capri, Cape Town, 7975 | linkedin.com/in/camadams007

#### **ABOUT ME**

Born and raised in the Deep South of Cape Town. I developed a keen interest in Maths and Physics at High School and completed a B.Sc in Maths and Computers at UCT. I then traveled a year in Asia and Europe before completing an Honors in Computer Science at UCT. Worked at SOLIDitech for 3 years as a full stack Java/HTML/CSS/React developer. Currently independently creating apps and freelancing.

### **SKILLS & ABILITIES**

Solid understanding of a wide range of topics and technologies across the web and software development spectrum. Knowledgeable Java, Node, Linux, Typescript, React, RDBMS, TailwindCSS, Prisma/Drizzle ORM, AWS, TeamCity, Vercel, VSCode, Git, React Native, WordPress and PHP.

Firm grasp on many programming concepts (e.g. data structures and OOP).

Self motivated and can quickly adapt & adjust to new challenges.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **CamTheHuman.com**, Cape Town—Senior Software Engineer (June 2024 - now)

- Built an Airbnb listings notifier with NextJS, ReactJS, NodeJS, AWS and Postgresql. bnbnotifier.com.
- Built an MVP for a Crypto Wallet Analyser using various Web3 APIs and the same stack as above for a freelance client

# **SOLIDitech (Pty) Ltd, Cape Town** — *Intermediate Software Engineer* (April 2021 - May 2024)

- Developed a reseller system for MWEB, a major client with millions of internet customers. My main achievement involved incorporating specific billing discount logic into complex legacy billing code.
- Migrated a long standing client at SOLIDitech to a newer billing system.
- Developed a stock delivery project using third-party stock APIs to verify and set aside stock and to coordinate contractors for installing stock at customers' homes.
- Trained and onboarded a new starter where I regularly assisted with explaining code and doing code reviews.

#### **Micro Brewing SA, Cape Town**— *Embedded Systems Developer* (June 2018 - July 2018)

- Collaborated with an engineer and a brewmaster to create an Arduino Script for automating a can filler and seamer.

## **Sunrise Productions, Cape Town** — *Junior IT Support Engineer Internship* (Nov 2019 - Jan 2020)

- Helped set up Sunrise Studios' new animation studio which involved installing network equipment such as a large file server and network switches.
- Managed their Linux intranet of computers dedicated to rendering animations.

# **EDUCATION**

**University of Cape Town** — *B.Sc Computer Science and Mathematics* (Jan 2016 - Dec 2018)

**University of Cape Town** — B.Sc (Hons) Computer Science (Jan 2020 - Dec 2020)

# **PROJECTS**

**Pathfinding Visualization** — camthehuman.com/pathfinding (Completed Feb 2021)

A visualization of Dijkstra's algorithm, a shortest path algorithm, using a Javascript library p5.js. Leveled up in: Algorithms, data structures, HTML, JavaScript, CSS.

#### **Spotify API** — camthehuman.com/spotify (Completed March 2024)

Most of the Artists in my "Liked Songs" playlist I didn't follow, on Spotify or Instagram. Since it took like 4 clicks to follow an artists, I wanted a faster way to follow all/most the artists in my "Liked Songs" playlist Leveled up in: Javascript concepts (Promise.all), NextJS, REST API development, Authentication

# **BNBNotifier** — camthehuman.com/bnbnotifier (Completed August 2024)

I made a product that could benefit my life- I used Airbnb a lot to find accommodation so I wanted a service that could notify of new listings in an area I was searching for.

Leveled up in: AWS, Authentication, CRON jobs, Vercel, Web Scraping